<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="xml.css"?>
<doc>
<!-- Testcase: bft_broswer_xml.xml -->
<!-- Description: To test XML rendering -->
<!-- Author:  Christine Dreckman  Date: 4/6/99 -->
<!-- CONFIDENTIAL AND PROPRIETARY TEST SCRIPT OF NETSCAPE COMMUNICATIONS CORPORATION Copyright © 1999 Netscape Communications Corporation. All Rights Reserved. Use of this Test Script is subject to the terms of the applicable license agreement from Netscape Communications Corporation -->
<topPart>
<exampleOne>
This is a block element: color is blue; font-size is 14pt; text is center aligned; margin-top is 50px; margin-bottom is 10px; border is solid black
</exampleOne>
<exampleTwo>
This is a block element. The text is red and in italics.
</exampleTwo>
</topPart>
<exampleThree xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40">
<html:b>This example uses <html:i><html:font color="#008080">XML Namespace</html:font></html:i> functionality. The box margins and border color are dictated by the linked CSS stylesheet. The border is solid lime and the margin is .50in. The &#60;B&#62;, &#60;I&#62; and &#60;FONT&#62; elements are used through the namespace functionality, which binds this xml element to the HTML 4.0 DTD. The text is bolded with the word 'XML Namespace' italicized in teal.</html:b>
</exampleThree>
<exampleFour>
This is a block element with the following values: the box floats to the right; the background color is yellow; the box is 300px wide; the border is black and 10px wide; the padding is 10px on all sides; the margin is 10px on all sides
</exampleFour>
<exampleFive>
This is a block element. The text should be cleared of the floating box above. There are no other values assigned to this block element.
</exampleFive>
<exampleSix>
<item>This is a list item in an unordered list. The list is bordered in solid olive. The list item is designated by a circle which is outside the list block
</item>
<item>This is a list item in an unordered list. The list is bordered in solid olive. The list item is designated by a circle which is outside the list block
</item>
<item>This is a list item in an unordered list. The list is bordered in solid olive. The list item is designated by a circle which is outside the list block
</item>
</exampleSix>
<exampleSeven xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40">
<html:p>This is another example using XML Namespace functionality. This box contains a paragraph and an image. The box is bordered in fuchsia, dictated by the linked CSS stylesheet. The paragraph and image elements are used through the namespace functionality, which binds this xml element to the HTML 4.0 DTD.
</html:p>
<html:img src="images/calanque.jpg" alt="image" width="400" height="247">
</html:img>
</exampleSeven>
</doc>