<?xml version='1.0'?>
<element name="A">
  <attributes>
    <coreAttributes/>
    <i18nAttributes/>
    <eventAttributes/>
    <eventFocusAttributes/>
    <attribute name="charset" type="Charset">
      This attribute specifies the character encoding of the resource designated by the link. 
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="type" type="Content Type">
      This attribute specifies the content type of a piece of content that is being linked. 
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="name" type="Text (CDATA)">
      This attribute names the current anchor so that it may be the destination of another link. The value of this
      attribute must be a unique anchor name. The scope of this name is the current document. Note that this
      attribute shares the same name space as the id attribute. 
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="href" type="URL">
      This attribute specifies the location of a Web resource, thus defining a link between the current element (the
      source anchor) and the destination anchor defined by this attribute.
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="hreflang" type="Language Code">
      This attribute specifies the base language of the resource designated by href and may only be used when href
      is specified
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="rel" type="Link Type">
      This attribute describes the relationship from the current document to the anchor specified by the href
      attribute. The value of this attribute is a space-separated list of link types. 
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="rev" type="Link Type">
      This attribute is used to describe a reverse link from the anchor specified by the href attribute to the
      current document. The value of this attribute is a space-separated list of link types.
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="accessKey" type="Character">
      This attribute assigns an access key to an element. An access key is a single character from the document  
      character set. Pressing an access key assigned to an element gives focus to the element and activates it. When
      a user activates a link defined by the A element, NGLayout follows the link. 
      <p/>
      The invocation of access keys depends on the underlying system. For instance, on machines running MS Windows, 
      one generally has to press the "alt" key in addition to the access key. On Apple systems, one generally has to
      press the "cmd" key in addition to the access key. 
      <p/>
      NGLayout will underline the value of an access key in such a way as to emphasize its role and to
      distinguish it from other characters.
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="tabIndex" type="Number">
      This attribute specifies the position of the current element in the tabbing order for the current document. This
      value must be a number between 0 and 32767. The tabbing order defines the order in which elements will receive
      focus when navigated by the user via the keyboard (normally via the "tab" key). The tabbing order may include
      elements nested within other elements.
      <p/>
      Elements that may receive focus are navigated by NGLayout according to the following rules:</p>
      <ol>
        <li>Those elements that support the tabindex attribute and assign a positive value to it are navigated first.
            Navigation proceeds from the element with the lowest tabindex value to the element with the highest value. Values
            need not be sequential nor must they begin with any particular value. Elements that have identical tabindex values
            should be navigated in the order they appear in the document source.</li>
        <li>Those elements that do not support the tabindex attribute or support it and assign it a value of "0" are
            navigated next. These elements are navigated in the order they appear in the document source.</li>
        <li>Elements that are disabled do not participate in the tabbing order.</li>
      </ol>
    </attribute>
  </attributes>
  
  <properties>
    <CoreElementProperties/>
    <HTMLElementProperties/>
  </properties>

  <methods>
    <CoreElementMethods/>
    <method name="blur">
      <description>Removes keyboard focus from this element.</description>
      <parameters/>
      <returns/>
      <exceptions/>
    </method>
    <method name="focus">
      <description>Gives keyboard focus to this element.</description>
      <parameters/>
      <returns/>
      <exceptions/>
    </method>
  </methods>

  <resources>
    <resource icon="w3c.gif" url="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/struct/links.html#edef-A">
      HTML 4.0 Recommendation, Section 12.2: The "A" element
    </resource>
    <resource icon="w3c.gif" url="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-DOM-Level-1/level-one-html.html#ID-48250443">
      DOM Level 1 HTML Recommendation: the HTMLAnchorElement interface 
    </resource>
    <resource icon="netscape.gif" url="http://developer.netscape.com/docs/manuals/htmlguid/tags7.htm#1227754">
       Netscape Navigator 4.0 documentation for the "A" element
    </resource>
    <resource icon="ie5.gif" url="http://www.microsoft.com/workshop/author/dhtml/reference/objects/A.asp">
      Microsoft Internet Explorer 5.0 documentation for the "A" element
    </resource>
  </resources>
</element>
