<?xml version='1.0'?>
<element name="APPLET">
  <navigationParent name="Global Structure" href="global.html"/>
  <overview>
    The APPLET element allows authors to embed a Java applet in an HTML document. 
  </overview>
  <HTMLSyntaxRequirements>
    One of the code or object attributes is required. If both code and object are given, 
    it is an error if they provide different class names. 
  </HTMLSyntaxRequirements>
  <attributes>
    <coreAttributes/>
    <i18nAttributes/>
    <eventAttributes/>
    <attribute name="codebase" type="URL">
     This attribute specifies the base URL for the applet. If this attribute is not 
     specified, then it defaults the same base URL as for the current document. 
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="code" type="Text (CDATA)">
      This attribute specifies either the name of the class file that contains the applet's 
      compiled applet subclass or the path to get the class, including the class file itself. 
      It is interpreted with respect to the applet's codebase. 
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="name" type="Text (CDATA)">
      This attribute specifies a name for the applet instance, which makes it possible 
      for applets on the same page to find (and communicate with) each other. 
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="archive" type="URL List">
      This attribute specifies a comma-separated list of URLs for archives containing classes and other resources that will be
      "preloaded". The classes are loaded using an instance of an AppletClassLoader with the given codebase. Relative URLs
      for archives are interpreted with respect to the applet's codebase. Preloading resources can significantly improve the
      performance of applets. 
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="object" type="Text (CDATA)">
      This attribute names a resource containing a serialized representation of an applet's state. It is interpreted relative to the
      applet's codebase. The serialized data contains the applet's class name but not the implementation. The class name is used
      to retrieve the implementation from a class file or archive. 
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="width" type="Length">
      This attribute specifies the initial width of the applet's display area (excluding any windows or dialogs that the applet
      creates). 
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="height" type="Length">
      This attribute specifies the initial height of the applet's display area (excluding any windows or dialogs that the applet
      creates). 
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="alt" type="Text">
      While NGLayout is loading applets, or if it cannot display them, it may use this attribute 
      to display alternate text. The language of the alternate text is specified by the lang attribute. 
    </attribute>
  </attributes>
  <properties>
    <CoreElementProperties/>
    <HTMLElementProperties/>
  </properties>
  <methods>
    <CoreElementMethods/>
  </methods>
  <examples>
    <example intro="In the following example, the APPLET element includes a Java applet in the document. Since no codebase is supplied, the applet is assumed to be in the same directory as the current document.">
      <APPLET code="Bubbles.class" width="500" height="500">
        Java applet that draws animated bubbles.
      </APPLET>
    </example>
  </examples>
  <resources>
  </resources>
</element>